{
    "id": "744bea982f7a41639aef6510729c0022",
    "title": "Simple Past vs. Simple Present vs. Present Perfect vs. Past Perfect",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I ................................ for hours but he didn’t come.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "waited",
                "wait",
                "have waited"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "275af47dd7da4eada42c1a4ffe40b922"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ..................................... in several movies.",
            "description": "We often use the present perfect to give news. ",
            "answers": [
                "acted",
                "has acted",
                "acts"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "59760836aea94899a71c4d7f0eea328c"
        },
        {
            "question": "The train ………………………….. a few minutes ago.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "leaves"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ba55b2c5a2834347bcb1514642f2be97"
        },
        {
            "question": "Make sure that you ………………………… on time.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "have arrived",
                "arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3f261609bb6e462791cfa88ab57b9cd4"
        },
        {
            "question": "The poor man made sure that his children never ………………………..",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too will be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "starve",
                "starved",
                "have starved"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6ec50e8ee3f4436fae3d1e9c0f1d203b"
        },
        {
            "question": "You will get the promotion if you ………………………….. it.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "deserve",
                "deserved",
                "have deserved",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b596835f87824d469d5bd72b1aa21bc6"
        },
        {
            "question": "They realized that they ………………………… a major blunder.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used for the earlier of the two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "committed",
                "have committed",
                "had committed"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c8b4ee248a4846a18e4ad03c3bfa5960"
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………………. anything from them in over a month.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "did not hear",
                "have not heard",
                "had not heard"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "994f409c7505450d9d620ad9f6082d4e"
        },
        {
            "question": "They …………………………. two wickets before rain interrupted the match.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "took",
                "have taken",
                "had taken"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d99b8ce66a9243a59e8a2425760b688e"
        },
        {
            "question": "Dad ………………………….. home from work at",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habits and routines. ",
            "answers": [
                "reaches",
                "has reached",
                "had reached"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f246101c0c5c47a984c8aece8df84760"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mother ………………………………. the weekends with her parents.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about facts and routines. ",
            "answers": [
                "spend",
                "spends",
                "has spent"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3251e52d23824e958c1e783384b297ee"
        },
        {
            "question": "She started crying as soon as she ………………………… me.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "has seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "bef992ec16c04c3f870a478f80f743ff"
        }
    ]
}